<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
	<section>
    <title>Final Rating - Pavel Jezek</title>
    <simplelist>
      <member>We picked up srcml for converting code in repository to xml.</member>
      <member>Github because of my previous knowledge of github </member>
      <member>C# as most of us had previous experience with this language</member>
    </simplelist>
	</section>	
	<section>
    <title>What I did</title>
    <simplelist>
      <member>Developmnet of frontend</member>
      <member>Debugging api</member>
    </simplelist>
	</section>
	<section>
    <title>Problems</title>
    <para>
      We chose Angular for our frontend development. As I was quite new to the whole idea of Angular I had to learn the basics before I started writing a code. One of the first issues I came across was hidding elements in index.html which isn't part of any view. This was solved by creating a controller that would handle elements outside particular views.
    </para>
    <para>
      Few other things I had to learn were sharing variables between views, creating http requests, handling xml in javascript.
    </para>
    <para>
      Since there is no native support for XML in javascript we had to find a library that would do so. We chose x2js. It is used to parse recieved xml data into a json object which can be handled more easily in javascript. This library doesn't create an ideal looking json object thought and reading data from it is a bit obscure.
    </para>
    <para>
      For visualising data returned from our API I chose to use charts. As I didn't want to waste time creating my own chart component I decided to look for suitable one online. I settled of angular-char.js based on Chart.js which was easy to use and sufficient for out purposes. I then decided to use line charts and doughnut charts based on the data I recieved.
    </para>
    <para>
      As I wanted the frontend not only to be functional, but also look pretty I decided to go with some simple animations and styling. I used a simple web tool coloors.co to help me choose a good combination of colours and then simple CSS3 stylings to create loading circle animation for when there is nothing to be shown in the chart yet and few other grapical features. I combined this with hidding elements from within the Angular itself.
    </para>
    <para>
      Lastly I wanted to try and make our app run on Microsofts Azure cloud service. This should be a simple process but as we used Mono instead of .NET itself this appeared to be a difficult thing to do. It seems there is a problem with running Mono apps on latest IIS since we couldn't get our app running even in latest Visual Studio. After hours of addressing this issue we decided to lay it aside as it seems there is no solution for this issue at the moment.
    </para>
	</section>
  <section>
    <title>Summary</title>
    <para>
      In this project I learned a lot about git and cooperation. As I have never used github in a bigger project and with more people then myself it was a bit difficult for me to get oriented in the process but it helped me a lot and now I understand all the different functions of git. Cooperation with other team members was very inspiring since we all brought a lot of good ideas.
    </para>
    <para>
      Learning Angular was fun and I found it to be very exciting way of creating web pages and applications. Integrating XML was interesting since I have previously only used JSON in similar projects.
    </para>
  </section>
</article>
